In the previous lecture, we looked at a public key
在之前的课程中 我们学习了公钥
encryption system that is built from the RSA,
加密系统 是基于RSA的
or more generally from trapdoors functions.
或者更一般的是来自陷门函数
In this lecture, we are going to look at public key encryption
这节课 我们将学习公钥加密
schemes that are build from the Diffie-Hellman protocol.
方案 这是基于diffie - hellman协议的
So, first recall that a public key encryption system is
先来回顾公钥加密系统 这里有
made up of three algorithms. There is a key
三个算法 有一个密钥
generation algorithm that I will denote by Gen,
生成算法由Gen表示
that basically generates a public key and a
可以生成一个公钥和
secret key. And then there are two algorithms: E
私钥 然后这里有两个算法 E
and D that encrypt and decrypt. And the point is
和D分别是加密和解密算法 重点是
the encryption algorithm encrypts using the
加密算法加密时用的是
public key and the decryption algorithm decrypts
公钥 解密算法解密时
using the secret key. The physical world analogy for
用的是私钥 物理世界中类似
public key encryption is a locked box, where anyone
公钥加密是一个锁箱 任何人
can put a message inside the box and then lock the
都可以置消息于箱子中 然后锁上
box, that corresponds to the public key and then
箱子 和公钥对应 而且
no one can open this box, except the person who has
没有人可以打开这个箱子 除了
the secret key, that has the key can put it in the
拥有私钥的人 他的钥匙可以插入
lock, unlock the box and the recover the message in
锁中 解锁箱子 恢复箱子里的消息
the box. Now, in the previous lecture, we looked at
之前的课程 我们学习了
a number of applications for public key encryption.
很多公钥加密的应用
In particular, we looked at the key exchange
特别的 我们研究了密钥交换
application, in fact, this is how public key encryption
的应用 事实上 这就是SSL中如何
is used in SSL, where the server sends its public
使用公钥加密 服务器将公钥发送
key to the browser, the browser chooses a secret
到浏览器 浏览器选择一个私钥
and then encrypts the secret using the server's
然后用服务器公钥加密秘密
public key, sends it back to the server, the
将其发送到服务器
server decrypts and now both the browser and the
服务器解密  现在浏览器和
server have a common secret that they can then
服务器有了公共的秘密信息 就可以
use to encrypt data, going back and forth, between
用它加密数据 在他们之间交互
them. So, in the interactive settings, such as in a
在交互设置中 像这样在一个
networking protocol, public key encryption would
网络协议中 公钥加密
primarily be used for setting up shared symmetric key
主要是被用于建立共享的对称密钥
which the two parties can then use to exchange
通信双方可以用它来交换
information. However, there are many settings
信息 然而 这有很多设置
where interaction is simply not possible and then
其交互就不可能的 那么
public key encryption is directly used to encrypt
公钥加密直接用于加密
messages. One example of this is secure email.
消息 对此有个例子是安全邮件系统
The email system in some sense is designed to be non-
邮件系统在某种意义上更适合于非
interactive, in the sense that the sender sends an
交互系统 在某种意义上 发送者发送一个
email, the email travels from relay to relay, to
邮件 邮件在中继之间传送
relay, until it finally arrives at the destination
直到最后到达目的地
and the destination should be able to decrypt,
目的地会有人可以解密
without interacting with the sender at that point.
不用与这边的发送者交互
That can be done basically, by the sender
这可以做到 基本上 借助于发送者
encrypting the message using the recipient's public
使用接收者的公钥加密这个消息
key. The ciphertext would travel along the SMTP chain
密文会沿着SMTP链传送
until it reaches the recipient. The recipient would
直到到达接收者那里 接收者会
use a secret key and recover the original sent
使用密钥去恢复原始发送的消息
message. However, there are many other cases
然而 有很多其他情况下
where interaction is not possible and I want to show
交互是不可能的 我想要给你们介绍
you two such cases. The first example is
这两种情况 第一个例子是
file systems. And in fact, public key encryption is a
文件系统 事实上 公钥加密是一个
good way to manage file sharing, in an encrypted file
管理文件共享的好方法 在加密文件系统
system. So, let me show you what I mean
我来解释这是什么意思
by that. So, imagine we have our friend Bob
想象我们的朋友Bob在这里
here, who wants to store an encrypted file on some
他想把一个加密文件存储在某个
storage server. So, he will go ahead and write the
存储服务器中 所以他要继续把
encrypted file to the storage server. What he
加密文件写到存储服务器中 其实
actually writes in the server is basically the
他写到服务器里的是如下内容：
following: he will generate a random file encryption key, we
他要产生一个随机文件加密密钥
will call it 'K sub F' and then he will use the
我们称之为Kf（下标） 然后他会使用用密钥Kf
symmetric encryption system to encrypt the file
用对称加密的方法
using the key 'K sub F'. Then, he will encrypt the
去加密文件，然后加密
key 'K sub F', using his own public key. So public key
密钥Kf' 用他所拥有的公钥 即Bob的公钥
of Bob. This will give Bob access to the file at a later
这可以使得Bob稍后有权限访问那个文件
time, right. Using his secret key, Bob can decrypt
好 使用私钥 Bob可以解密消息开头
this header, recover 'K sub F'. Then he will
恢复Kf 然后就可以
decrypt the actual encrypted file and recover the
解密实际的加密文件 恢复
plaintext file. So, decryption will work in two steps.
明文文件 所以 解密工作有两步
However, Bob now wants also to give access to
但是 Bob现在想让Alice也有权限
Alice, to this file. What he will do is, he will go
访问这个文件 他要做的就是继续下去
ahead and in addition he will also include in the
在文件头里面另外也加入
file header, an encyption of 'K sub F' under Alice's
一个用Alice的公钥加密的Kf'
public key. OK. So, notice that there was no
好 注意这里没有交互
interaction here. All that Bob knows is Alice's public
Bob现在只知道的是Alice的公钥
key and yet he was able to the make the file
但他能够将文件访问权
accesible to Alice at a later time.
稍后授权于Alice
So, now Bob disappears and then Alice
现在Bob走了 然后Alice
comes and accesses the disk at a later time.
过来 稍后接手这个磁盘
She will read the ciphertext, decrypt  her part of
她能看到密文 解密她那部分的
the header, recover Kf and then she can decrypt
文件头 恢复Kf 然后就可以解密
the symmetrically encrypted file and recover the
这个对称加密文件 恢复
actual file contents. Ok, so you can see that without
实际的文件内容 好 你们可以看见
any interaction, Bob was able to write to the file
无需任何交互 Bob可以对这个文件系统进行写操作
system and enable Alice to access the file, as well.
赋予Alice对文件的访问权 还有
Again, at the time that Alice was reading the file, there is no
当Alice在读这个文件的时候 是不能
interaction with Bob, because maybe Bob is already
与Bob交互的 因为可能已经找不到Bob了
inaccesible and yet Alice can still read the file
但目前Alice可以读取
recovered by herself.
自己恢复的文件
So, another example of a non-interactive
另外一个关于无交互应用的
application of public key encryption is what's called
公钥加密的例子叫做
key escrow. Now, key escrow may actually sound
密钥托管 也许这听起来
like a bad thing but in fact it is a mandatory
像是一件坏事情 但事实上它是
feature in corporate environments. So, the idea
公司环境中的强制性特征 所以这里的
here is this. So imagine Bob writes data to a
概念就是这个 想象Bob对
disk and then later Bob becomes inaccesible.
磁盘写数据 然后走了
Maybe Bob is fired. Maybe Bob is out sick.
假设是Bob被解雇 或者生病了
And somehow the company needs to have access to
公司在某种情况下需要访问
Bob's files. So having Bob be the only one
Bob的文件 那只能Bob可以解密
able to decrypt these files is simply unacceptable in
这些文件的情况在公司环境是不适用
corporate settings. The corporation might need
的 公司可能需要
access to those files. So, the question is what to do.
访问这些文件 那问题就是如何做到这一点
And the answer is to introduce this entity called
答案是介绍这个实体名为
a key escrow service. The way the system then
密钥托管服务 这个体系的
would work is as follows:
运行方式如下
Basically, when Bob writes his file to disk, his
基本上 当Bob向磁盘写他的文件时 他的
system, as it's writing the file to this shared
系统 就是他将文件里的内容写到这个共享的
storage medium, what it would do of course, as before,
存储介质 这当然跟以前的一样
it would encrypt the file using the file encryption key Kf.
他会用文件加密密钥Kf加密这个文件
It would encrypt Kf using Bob's public key, but it would
用Bob的公钥加密这个Kf 但也会
also encrypt Kf using an escrow service. So here,
用一个托管服务加密Kf 所以这里
the escrow service is completely offline. We never
托管服务是完全离线的 我们不
talk to it unless we actually need its services.
提到这个 除非我们真的需要这个服务
As Bob is writing the file, all he does is he simply writes
当Bob在写文件 他所做的就只是将
the encryption of Kf under the escrow authority's
托管组织公钥下的Kf加密的内容
public key into the file header. Now, later Bob
写到文件头 然后Bob
disappears and now the company needs to recover
离开了 现在公司需要恢复
Bob's file. What does it do? Well, at this point it would
Bob的文件 该怎么做？ 好 此时他们
contact the escrow service. The escrow service
应该联系托管服务 托管服务
would read this part of the header, use its secret
会读取这部分的文件头 用其私钥
key to decrypt the header and recover Kf and then use Kf
解密头文件来恢复Kf 然后用Kf
to decrypt the actual file.
去解密世纪文件
Ok. So, in this way again you notice that  the escrow service was
好 这种方法下你们也能注意到 托管服务是
completely offline. There was no interaction with the
完全离线的 公司与托管服务
escrow service until the point at which the escrow
没有交互 除非是真正需要
services were actually needed. And again, you can
托管的时候 同样可以看到
see that this is a very clean and elegant application
这是一个非常干净简洁的的
of public key encryption. So, as I said in the
公钥加密应用 如我在前面的
previous lecture, we saw constructions for public
课程中所说 我们看到了基于
key encryption based on trapdoor functions.
陷门函数的公钥加密结构
In particular, we look at RSA. We looked at the
特别的 我们来看RSA 我们学过
generic construction we called ISO standard.
通用的结构 名为ISO标准
We looked at constructions like OAEP+ and so on and so forth.
也学过像OAEP+等结构
In this lecture, we are going to look at public key
这节课我们要学习的公钥结构
constructions from the Diffie-Hellman protocol.
来自Diffie-Hellman协议
This is another family of public key systems and
这是公钥系统的另一个类别
I am going to show you how they work. These public
我来介绍他们是如何工作的这些公钥
key systems are generally called ElGamal public key
系统通常被称为EIGamal公钥
encryption schemes. Taher ElGamal was actually Marty
加密体制 Taher ElGamal其实是Marty
Hellman's student. He came up with this ElGamal
Hellman的学生 他想到这个EIGamal
encryption system as part of his PhD thesis.
加密系统作为其PhD论文的一部分
And, in fact, ElGamal encryption, for historical
其实ElGamal加密 因历史
reasons, is used in an email encryption system called GPG,
原因 被用于名为GPG的邮件加密系统
the GNU Privacy Guard. As usual, when we
GNU隐私保护 一如既然 当我们
construct public key encryption systems, our goal is
构建公钥加密系统 我们的目标是
to build systems that have chosen ciphertext security,
构建有选择密文安全的系统
so that they are secure both against eavesdropping
所以同时具有针对窃听和篡改
and tampering attacks. So, before I show you the ElGamal
攻击的安全性 所以在我介绍ELGamal
system let's do a very brief review of the Diffie-Hellman
系统之前 我们先来对Diffie-Hellman协议
protocol. So, in my description here, I am going
简短复习 在我的描述中 我要
to abstract a little bit from the version that we saw last
从我们上周版本中摘取一小部分
week. In fact, I just going to use the concept
其实 我只是想借用
of a finite cyclic group. In fact, we have an arbitrary finite
有限循环群的概念 事实上 比如我们有一个任意的有限
cyclic group, for example, it could be the group (Zp) star,
循环群 可以是群（Zp）
but it could also be the points of an elliptic curve.
它也可以是椭圆曲线上的点群
And as I mentioned, there are some benefits to doing
如我提到的 将Diffie-Hellman对应到
Diffie-Hellman over an elliptic curve. But, for simplicity,
椭圆曲线上有好处 但是为了简单起见
I am just going to refer to G as an abstract finite
我只提到G作为抽象的有限
cyclic group, but in your heads you should be
循环群 但是在你们脑海里 你们应该
thinking G is the group (Zp) and let's suppose
想象G是群（Zp） 我们来假设
that the group has order n for some integer n.
这个集合阶为n
Now, we are going to fix a generator g of this group
现在我们要选定这个群的一个生成元
and all this means, is basically, if you look at the
这就表示 基本上 如果你研究一下
successive powers of g, that basically you get
g的连续次数 那就可以得到
all the elements in the group G. You notice,
集合G里面的所有元素 注意
because the group has order n, we know that
因为集合有n阶 我们知道
g to the power of n is equal to 1. And, therefore
g的n次方等于1 因此
there is no reason to go beyond the n-1st power
不需要超过g的n-1次方
of g. g to the n is equal to 1 so that we just wrap around.
g的n次方等于1 我们就绕回来了
Ok. So, we have this cyclic group G. We have this
好 我们有了这个循环群G 有了
generator whose powers gave us all the elements of
生产元 它的幂次生成G的所有元素
G, and now let me remind you how the Diffie-Hellman
现在我来介绍Diffie-Hellman协议的
protocol works. Basically, what Alice does is she  chooses a
工作原理 基本上 Alice所做的就是她选择
random a. She computes g to the a and sends it
一个随机数a 然后计算g的a次方并把它
over to Bob. Bob chooses a random b. Let's see who
发送给Bob Bob选择了一个随机数b 我们来看有谁
remembers. What does Bob send over to Alice?
记得 Bob给Alice发送的什么
So, Bob sends over to Alice g to the b and of
好 Bob将g的b次方发送给了Alice
course I should remind you that both g to the a and
当然我要提醒你们 g的a次方和
g to the b are just elements in this group G. Now,
g的b次方都是集合G中的元素 现在
they can derive the shared secret, If you remember,
他们可以获得导处共享秘密 如果你们记得
the shared secret is g to the ab, and these equalities
共享密钥是g的ab次方 这些等式
here shows that both sides can actually compute
表明双方实际上都可以算得
the shared secret given the values at their disposal.
他们发送的值里隐含的共享秘密
So, Alice for example, has B and she has a, and
所以 比如Alice有B 也有a
so raising B to the power of a, gives her the shared
计算B的a次方 她就能得到共享密钥
secret. The attacker, of course, the poor attacker
攻击者 当然 弱攻击者
he gets to see A and B and his goal is now,
得到了A和B 现在他的目标是
of course, he also gets to see the generated g, and
当然 他还得到了生成元g
his goal now is to compute g to the ab. But, we said that
现在他的目标是计算g的ab次方 但是 我们讲过
this is believed to be a hard problem. Given g, g to the a,
这的确是个难题 给定g g的a次方
and g to the b, in a group like  Zp, computing g to
以及g的b次方 在一个集合比如Zp 计算g
the ab is difficult. So, now let's see how to convert to
的ab次方很难 所以 我们来看怎么将
the Diffie-Hellman protocol into an actual public key
DH协议转换到一个实际的公钥系统
system. As I said, this was a brilliant idea due to
如我所讲 这是Taher EIGamal的一个杰出的注意
Taher ElGamal. So, as before, we are going to fix our
所以 一如既往 我们要准备我们的
cyclic group G and a generator g inside of G.
循环域G 和生成元G里面的g
Now, here I wrote the Diffie-Hellman protocol again,
现在 这里我再写一次DH协议
except now we are going to assume that these guys
就是我们现在要假设这些东西
are separated in time. These two steps do not have
在时间上是离散的 这两步不用
to occur simultaneously; they could actually take place
同时出现 实际上它们可以在不同
at quite different times. The first step of the Diffie-Hellman
的时刻发生 DH协议的第一步
protocol is what we are going to view as key
是我们要研究的密钥
generation. That is the public key is going to be
生成 那是因为公钥要用这个
this capital A  and the secret key is simply going to
大写字母A表示 私钥就用这个
be the little a. So, you notice of course that
小写字母a表示 当然你们可以注意到
extracting the secret key from the public key,
从公钥中提取私钥
namely extracting the little a from capital A is a
也就是从大写字母A得出小a是
discrete log problem. So, that recovering a secret
离散对数问题 所以 恢复私钥
key is actually difficult. Ok, now this gives us our public key.
实际上很困难 好 现在我们得到了公钥
So, now at a later time Bob wants to encrypt a
那等会儿Bob会加密一个消息并
message to Alice, encrypted using her public key.
发送给Alice 用她的公钥加密
So how does Bob encrypt? Well, what he is going to do is
那么Bob是怎么加密的呢？他会这么做
he's going to compute his contribution to the Diffie-Hellman
他计算在DH协议中他的部分
protocol. Namely, he is going to send over g to the
即，他把g的b次方发出去
little b. Of course, he is going to choose this little b
当然他会随机地选择小b
at random and now he is going to compute by
现在他会自己算
himself the shared secret. So, he is going to
共享密钥 即他就可以计算
compute by himself g to the ab. From this g to the ab
g的ab次方，从这个g的ab次方
he is going to derive a symmetric key for a
他能得到对称密码系统的对称密钥
symmetric encryption system and then he is going to
接着他会
encrypt the message m using this symmetric key
用这个对称密钥对消息m加密
that he just derived. And that is the pair he is going to
他刚推导出来的密钥 这就是他会发送的密钥组
send. So, he is going to send over his contribution
那么他把自己在
to the Diffie-Hellman protocol plus the symmetric
DH协议中部分和经过对称
encryption of the message m that he wants to send
加密的消息m，他想发给Alice
over to Alice. Ok, so you can see basically, we are
的消息m。好，现在你基本可以发现 我们
doing the exact same thing as we would do in the Diffie-Hellman
和在DH协议中一样，我们进行同样的操作
protocol except now we, Bob directly immediately is using
除了现在，Bob直接立即就使用
his Diffie-Hellman secret to encrypt the message  that he
他的DH秘密信息他要
wants to send over to Alice.
发送给Alice的加密消息
Now, what does Alice do to decrypt?
现在，Alice怎么解密呢？
Basically, she is going also to compute the
基本上，她会计算
Diffie-Hellman secret. Remember, that now she just
DH秘密信息 回忆一下 她现在
received Bob's contribution to the Diffie-Hellman
刚收到Bob在DH协议中的部分
protocol and she has her secret key a. So, she can
她有自己的秘密钥a，因此她可以
compute also the Diffie-Hellman secret, namely
计算DH秘密信息即
g to the ab, from which she is going to derive the
g的ab次方，从这个她可以导出
symmetric encryption key k. And then, she is going
对称密钥k，接着，她会
to decrypt the message to recover the actual
解密消息恢复出
plaintext. Ok, so that is the intuition for how we
真正的明文 好这是我们直观的解释
convert the Diffie-Hellman protocol into a public key
如何把DH协议转换成一个公钥加密
system. By the way, this was kind of an interesting
系统 通过这种方法 这是一种比较有意思的
development at the time that it came out,  partially
的改进方法，在一开始的时候 部分因为
because, you notice this is a randomized encryption scheme.
你注意到，这是一个随机加密体制
So, every time Bob encrypts a message, it is
因此，每次Bob加密一个消息
required that he choose a new random b and
需要他随机选一个b
encrypt the message using this new random b.
用这个新的随机数b对消息进行加密
So, let's see the ElGamal system,  actually in more
我们看一下ElGamal系统 更详细的
detail. So, now actually let's  view it as an actual
即我们认为它是一个实际的
public key encryption system. Namely, algorithm Gen,
公钥密码系统，即算法Gen
algorithm E and algorithm D.
算法E和算法D
So, as usual, we are going to fix our finite cyclic
所以，和往常一样，我们研究一下我们的有限
group of order n. Another ingredient that we are going
n阶循环群。我们需要的另外一个因素是
to need is a symmetric encryption system. So, I am
一个对称加密机制。因此我
going to refer to it as E sub s, and D sub s. These are the
用Es和Ds标识这个。这是
encryption and decryption algorithms of a symmetric
一个对称加密系统的加密和解密算法
encryption system that happens to provide
它能够保证
authenticated encryption. And, the key space for
认证加密。这个系统的密钥空间是
this system is capital K. And, then we are also going
大K。这样，我们还需要一个
to need a hash function that maps pairs of elements
杂凑函数能把这些元素映射到群里
in the group, namely elements in G squared into
即把G平方映射到
the key space. Now, here is how the public key
密钥空间 现在 这是公钥密码系统的
encryption system works. So, I have to describe
工作方式 现在我们描述
three algorithms. Algorithm that generates the
一下这算个算法 算法生成
public key and the secret key, and then the  encryption
公钥和私钥 接着加密
and decryption algorithms. So, the key generation
和解密算法 密钥生成算法
algorithm works as follows: All we do is basically,
工作如下 我们所做的，基本上，
build up Alice's contribution to the Diffie-Hellman
构造Alice的DH协议部分
protocol. What we are going to do is going to choose a
接下来选择一个
random generator g in G and then we are going to
G中的随机生成元g， 选一个随机
choose a random exponent a. The secret key is
的指数a 密钥就是
going to be a and then the public key is going to be
a，公钥是
the generator g and Alice's contribution to the
生成元g和Alice的
Diffie-Hellman protocol. The reason, by the way,
DH协议部分，我们不用
we don't use a fix generator, is because it
固定的生成元的原因是
allows us to somewhat use a weaker assumption,
这样允许我们使用一个弱假设
improving security. And, so it is actually better to
提高安全性 而且每次都
choose a random generator every time. It is easy
选一个随机生成元好一些，选随机
enough to choose a random generator. All we do, is we
生成元很容易 我们要做的就是
take the generator that we started with and then we
选一个起始的生成元 然后
raise it to some power that is relatively prime to n.
求a次方，a与n互素
That will give us another generator. A random
就能给我们另外一个生成元了 一个随机的
generator of the group capital G. Ok. So, you can
群G的生成元 好。这样 你会
see here that again the public key is simply Alice's
发现这里公钥就是Alice
contribution to the Diffie-Hellman protocol. And, the
在DH协议中的部分
secret key is the random a that she chose. Now, how
密钥是她随机选择的 现在
do we encrypt and decrypt? Well, when Bob wants
我们怎么加密和解密呢？好 当Bob想
to encrypt the message, he is going to use the
加密一个消息时，他会使用公钥
public key. Remember, it consists of  g and h.
记着，它由g和h组成
Here, he wants to encrypt a message m.
这里 他要加密消息m
So, here is what he is going to do. So, he is going
所以 他会这么做，他
to choose his contribution to the Diffie-Hellman protocol.
先构造他的DH协议部分
So, this is the secret b that he would normally
他选择秘密信息b和在DH协议
choose in Diffie-Hellman. And, now he is going to
中一样，他计算
compute g to the b, which is actually his message,
g的b次方 实际上就是他的消息
that gets send to Alice in the Diffie-Hellman protocol.
在DH协议中他发给Alice的
He is going to compute the Diffie-Hellman secret,
他计算DH秘密信息
that's h to the b. If you remember, h was g to the a,
即h的b次方 如果你还记得 h是g的a次方
therefore, this value here is really g to the ab.
因此这个值实际上是g的ab次方
That's the Diffie-Hellman secret. That is the one thing that
这就是DH秘密消息 这是
the attacker doesn't actually know. Next, he is going
攻击者不知道的一部分消息 接着他
to compute a symmetric key by basically hashing
计算一个对称密钥 通过hash
this pair u comma v. So, u, of course, is something
u,v  这里u是
that the attacker is going to know because that is
攻击者会知道的，因为这会
going to be sent as part of the ciphertext. But v, the
作为密文的一部分公开传播 但是v
attacker isn't going to know. Again, for the proof of
攻击者不知道。对安全性的证明
security, actually it helps to hash both u and v. So, we
实际上hash u和v对证明有帮助。
hash both of them together. Although, strictly speaking
这样我们对这两个进行hash，但是，严格地说
we just needed to hash v, because v is the only value
我们只需要hash v，因为v是唯一攻击者
that the attacker doesn't know. The attacker
不知道的值。攻击者已经知道
already knows u, because that's going to be part of the data
u，因为它是在网络上传送的数据的一部分
that's sent on the network. So, anyhow, so Bob derives
不管怎么样 Bob
this symmetric key k, by hashing u and v. Then, he
导出这个密钥k 通过hash u和v 接着
goes ahead and encrypts the message using the
他继续加密消息
symmetric key k and finally he outputs his
就用这个密钥k 最后他输出他的
contribution to the Diffie-Hellman protocol.
DH协议部分
The value u and then the symmetric ciphertext that
u值，然后对称密文
directly encrypts the message m.
是对消息m的直接加密
That's it. So, the ciphertext consists of these two
好了 密文包括这两个
parts and that is the thing that gets sent over the
部分 这些是我们要通过网络
network. Let's see, how does Alice decrypt now.
传送的 现在看一下 Alice怎么解密
So, she is going to use her secret key a to decrypt
她会用她的密钥解密
and she receives here, Bob's contribution to the
她这里接收到的 Bob在
Diffie-Hellman protocol plus the symmetric
DH协议中的部分和对称
encryption of the message that Bob sent.
消息加密，Bob发过来的
What she will do is she'll compute herself the Diffie-Hellman
她要做的是计算她自己的DH秘密
secret. If you remember, u to the a is simply g to the b
消息 如果你记得 u的a次方就是g的b次方
to the a. Which is g to the ab. So, here Alice
的a次方，就是g的ab次方 这里Alice
computed the Diffie-Hellman secret. And, now let me
计算DH秘密信息 那么我问个问题
ask you, how does she derive the symmetric key k
她怎么得到对称密钥k
given the Diffie-Hellman secret, g to the ab and the
已知DH秘密信息 g的ab次方
ciphertext that she was given?
和她得到的密文
Well, what she will do, is simply again, now she has
好， 她这么做 还是很简单
u from the ciphertext and she has v, because she just
从密文中得到u，她有v，因为她刚才
computed it herself. So, now she can rederive the
自己通过计算得到 那么现在她可以通过
symmetric encryption key  by hashing u and v
对u和v进行hash得到
together to get the symmetric encryption key and
对称加密密钥
then she just decrypts the ciphertext to get the
用这个密钥对密文解密即
actual plaintext. OK, so that's it. That is the whole
得到明文 好 就这样
encryption and decryption algorithm. In a picture,
这就是整个加密算法和解密算法 如果图形化
the way the ciphertext would look, is also
密文看起来是这样的 和我们
as kind of what we saw in the last lecture. Basically,
上一讲看到的类似 基本上
there would be a short header that contains u.
这里会有一个短的头文件包含u
Which as you recall, is g to the b. And, then the rest of the
想一下，就是g的b次方 剩下的
ciphertext would be the encryption of the message
这部分密文就是对所传送消息的加密
that is being sent, under the symmetric key k.
用密钥k的加密
And, then to decrypt, Alice would use this header
接着 对解密 Alice会用这个头文件
to derive the Diffie-Hellman secret from which she
导出DH秘密信息 通过它，她可以
will derive k and then decrypts the body, to get the
导出k 然后对这个部分进行解密 以此
original plaintext. By the way, I should note that
得到原始的明文 通过这种方法 我要说明一下
the way I describe this system here, is actually not
我用来描述这个系统的方法实际上
how ElGamal described it originally, this is
并不是ElGamal最初用的方法 这是
in some sense a modern view about the ElGamal
一种现代视觉的解释ELGaml加密算法的
encryption, but it is pretty much equivalent to how
的方法 但是和ELGamal的观点等同
ElGamal viewed it. So, now let's look at the
那么 现在 让我们看一下
performance of ElGamal. So, here what I wrote
ElGamal的效率 这里我写的是
is the, kind of the time intensive steps of  ElGamal
ElGamal加密算法的核心步骤
encryption. Namely, during encryption, there are
即，加密中
these two exponentiations in the group G.
有两个群G上的指数运算
Exponentiation, remember is a cubic time algorithm
指数运算， 我们知道是立方时间的算法
using the repeated squaring algorithm. And, as a
如果使用重复平方算法的话
result, it is fairly time intensive. When I say, time
所以 很耗时间 当我说
intensive, I mean, that on a modern processor it would
耗时，我的意思是说 用现代的处理器
take a few milliseconds to compute these
它会花几个毫秒的时间计算
exponentiations and during decryption, basically,
这些指数运算 解密过程 基本上
the decryptor computes one exponentiation,
解密者只需要做一个指数运算
namely, u to the a. This is the bottleneck during
即 u的a次方 这是解密过程的瓶颈
decryption. Ok, so you would think that encryption
好 你会认为加密过程
actually is, takes twice as long as decryption, because
实际上 是解密时间的两倍 因为
encryption requires two exponentiations, while
加密需要两个指数运算 而
decryption requires only one. It turns out, that
解密只需要一个 但是 我们发现
is not entirely accurate because, you notice that the exponentiation
这并不一定精确 因为 你会注意到
during decryption is done to a variable basis.
解密过程的指数运算是对变化的底数
Namely, u changes every time. Whereas during
即，u每次都变 而在
encryption, the basis is fixed: g and h are derived
加密过程中 底数不变 g和h是从
from the public key and are fixed forever.
公钥导出来的，永远固定
So, in fact, in turns out that if you want to do
所以 实际上 如果你要
exponentiation to a fixed basis, you can do a lot of
对一个固定的底数做指数运算
precomputation. In particular, you can do all the
你可以进行大量的雨季算 尤其，你可以
squaring steps in the repeated squaring algorithm
利用重复平方算法，先离线做所有的平方运算
offline. So, here what you would do, you would
那么你现在要做的就是
compute all powers of 2 of g. So, you would
算所有g的2的次幂次方 也就是说你先算
compute g, g squared, g to the fourth, g to the
g， g的平方，g的4次方
eighth, go to the sixteenth, g to the thirty two, and so
g的8次方 g的16次方 g的32次方
on and so forth. These are all the squaring steps of
以此类推 这是你需要做的所有的平方步骤
the repeated squaring algorithm you would do offline.
当你用重复平法算法离线时
The same thing for h. And, then when it comes time to
对h是一样的 那么当你需要做
actually do the real exponentiation all you need to do is just do the
实际的真实的指数运算时你需要做的就是
multiplications, to accumulate these powers of 2 into the
相乘 令这些个2的幂次组成
exponent b, that you're trying to compute.
指数b 这就是你想要算的
So, if you think about it, this can actually speed up
所以，如果你好好想一下，这个就能加速
exponentiation by a factor of 3. In fact, it would
以指数运算，3倍加速，实际上
speed up it even more if you allow me to store even
如果你允许我存储更大的表那么速度会更快
larger tables. This is called a windowed exponentiation.
这个称为窗口法指数运算
But, regardless, if you allow the encryptor to
但是 无论如何 如果你允许加密者
store large tables that are derived from the public
存储多大的表格 从公钥导出来的表格
key, then in fact encryption is not going to be
实际上加密不会比
slower than decryption. In fact, encryption will be
解密慢，实际上 加密会比解密快
faster than decryption. But, again, this requires that
但是这个需要
the encryptor to precompute these large tables
解密者预计算这些很大的表格
and store them around. So, if all the encryptor is
并存储 所以 如果所有的解密者都这么
doing, is just constantly encrypting to a single
做 就是持续地加密给一个固定的
recipient, that can be done actually fairly fast using these
接受者 可以进行地相当快 使用这些
precomputed tables. If the encryptor, for every
预计算表 如果加密者 对每一个
message is encrypting to a different recipient, for
消息 是给不同的接受者 例如
example, if every time you send an email, you send
如果你每发一封邮件
an email to a different recipient, then, in fact, the
你发给不同的接受者 那么 实际上
encryption will be twice as slow as decryption.
会比解密慢1倍
So, this is a good trick to keep in mind. In fact, most
所以 这是一个应该记住的不错的技巧。实际上
cryptolibraries don't do this. So, if you see that you
大部分密码学库都不这么做 所以 如果你发现
are always encrypting to the same public key and
你总是用同样公钥加密并且
for some reason your encryption process takes a
因为某些原因你的加密过程很耗
lot of time, it's a bottleneck for you, keep in mind
时间 这就是你的瓶颈 记住你
that you can actually really speed things up
可以通过预计算的方法
using precomputation.
提速
Of couse, if encryption is a bottleneck for you, you
当然 如果加密是你的瓶颈 你也
might as well be using RSA, where an RSA encryption
可以用RSA RSA的速度是相当快的
is really fast. Ok, so that is the end of our
好 我们对ELGamal加密算法的描述
description of ElGamal encryption. Now, the next
到这里就结束了 现在 下一个问题就是
question of course, is why is the system secure,
当然 为什么这个系统是安全的
in particular, can we prove that it's chosen
尤其 我们能证明它
ciphertext secure and more importantly, under what
是选择密文安全的吗？更重要的是 在什么样的
assumptions can we prove that the system is
假设下我们可以证明这个系统是
chosen ciphertext secure? So, we are going to
选择密文安全的 所以 我们下一节将
discuss that in the next segment.
讨论这个部分